<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.1" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xila="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude/local-attributes"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:trans="http://docbook.org/ns/transclusion"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Towards a Canonical Form for British Blazons</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname>Karl</firstname><surname>Wilcox</surname></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Drawshield.net</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <releaseinfo>Version 0.1</releaseinfo>

    <pubdate>June 2021</pubdate>
  </info>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <sect1>
      <title>Purpose</title>

      <para>This document proposes a standard for the textual presentation of
      British blazons, the language used to describe items of heraldry. This
      presentation</para>

      <para>Three alternative, but wholly equivalent presentation methods are
      described:</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Minimised</emphasis> the shortest possible
      text description which still allows the entire heraldic device to be
      re-created.</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Plain Text</emphasis> A full, appropriately
      indented, description of the heraldic device.</para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Rich Text</emphasis> A full, appropriately
      indented, description of the heraldic device which uses additional font
      effects to further identify types of component.</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Definitions</title>

      <para>Since the presentation recommendations are based on the category
      of the heraldic term we must define these terms clearly. This section
      contains the category definitions. </para>

      <para>Sometimes these terms are used differently in the heraldic literature, however the
        definitions shown here are considered definitive for the purpose of this document and the
        presentation proposals. </para>

      <sect2>
        <title>Container Elements</title>

        <para>Container Elements contain other heraldic terms, they don't have
        a meaning on their own.</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Device</emphasis> we use this term to
        refer to any complete item of heraldic imagery. So this may be an
        entire achievement, a single shield image or any combination of other
        container elements. It is the "thing" that the blazon is intended to
        describe.</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Achievement</emphasis> - encompasses all
        other components, including the shield, crest, compartment, supporters
        and motto. This is the highest level of container. </para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Shield</emphasis> - this the variable
        shaped region containing the field, ordinaries and charges.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Marshalling</emphasis> - a container for two or more shields or
          further marshallings combined with the same device.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Sub-shield</emphasis> - (not a strictly heraldic term but useful
          when discussing marshalled shields).</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Crest</emphasis> - placed on top of the shield and consisting of
          helmets, bourlets and other charges. A shield may have more than one crest</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Supporters</emphasis> - charges placed either side of the
          shield.</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Compartment</emphasis> - charge which the
        shield rests upon.</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Mantling</emphasis> - decorative charge around and behind the
          shield</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Motto</emphasis> - ribbon like region containing a text-base
          charge </para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Shield Elements</title>

        <para>These are elements that primarily appear on the shield, although some may also appear
          as part of the crest, or as supporters</para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Field</emphasis> - the entire body of the shield itself</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Ordinary</emphasis> - a pre-defined shape in a fixed position on
          the field</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Charge</emphasis> - an abstract or concrete represenatation that
          can appear multiple times, in multiple locations and is subject to considerable
          variation</para>
        <para> </para>
      </sect2>
      <sect2>
        <title>Appearance Elements</title>
        <para/>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>
</book>
